UK / French / Lebanese nationalities Currently based in London, United Kingdom thomas@seropian.io https://uk.linkedin.com/in/tseropian

Tech Lead / Lead Software Engineer

Profile

I am a software engineer with 18 years of experience building tech solutions across several industries and a strong entrepreneurial focus. I am equally comfortable with hands-on delivery (i.e. writing code) and managing engineering teams (i.e. helping other developers write code). I help organisations embrace new technologies to solve challenging real-world problems and launch successful products that customers love.

Work experience

Principal Software Engineer for a digital production studio

Motif, London, United Kingdom – October 2023 until now (motifgroup.co)

ightarrow Responsible for an API-as-a-product and client applications and infrastructures.

Scoping, designing and building client web applications and starting a greenfield API-as-a-product focusing on intelligent packaging. Defining ways of working & software development lifecycle.

<u>Technology:</u> AWS, API design, TypeScript, Node.js, Serverless (Lambda), CDK, Docker, MySQL, Prisma, Redis.

Senior Software Engineer (contract-based), Remote / London, UK - Jul. to Sep. 2023

- → **Flowtrace**, UK-based company metrics tool provider Feb. to Sep. 2023 (<u>flowtrace.co</u>) Building new third-party data provider integrations for feeding into the core SaaS tool.
- \rightarrow **Bulb Energy,** UK-based green energy provider Mar. to Nov. 2022 (<u>bulb.co.uk</u>) via <u>YLD.io</u> Building new comms features for rolling out electric smart meter installations across the business.
- → **ApprenticeFS**, US-based life sciences startup Sep. 2021 to Dec. 2021 (<u>apprentice.io</u>)

 Building new features for an intelligent pharmaceutical manufacturing execution system SaaS platform.
- → **Condé Nast,** global publishing house Mar. to Sep. 2021 (<u>condenast.com</u>) via <u>YLD.io</u>

 Building an internal API & validation library for content migration of 50 publications to a new tech stack.
- → **Progressive Content,** marketing agency Sep. 2020 to Feb. 2021 (<u>progressivecontent.com</u>) Building a microservices backend for a UK-based banking client's content marketing CMS.
- → **AND Digital,** software consultancy Jul. 2019 to Apr. 2020 (<u>and.digital</u>)

 Leading a development team of 5 members in a cloud transformation project for a UK insurance client.

<u>Technology:</u> Node.js, Serverless, TypeScript, GraphQL, React, Docker, Kubernetes, DynamoDB, Elasticsearch, Github Actions, AWS, GCP, Azure, Terraform

Head of Engineering / Tech Lead for a health-tech startup

Skin Analytics, London, United Kingdom – October 2017 to May 2019 (skin-analytics.com)

→ Responsible for an API-as-a-product, internal and commercial applications and infrastructures.

Leading technical team (8 members between UK and Poland). Managing infrastructure. Day-to-day management, code reviews and testing. Delivered a Software as a Medical Device commercial API.

<u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, Serverless (Lambda), TypeScript, React, MySQL, MongoDB, Docker, Ansible.

Mentoring, since 2017

Since 2024 - MentorCruise: Mentoring about system design, software engineering, career orientation & more.

Since 2023 - GDG Academy program: Mentoring students in various UK universities.

2017-22 - Open Classrooms: Tutoring for the tech lead curriculum for a french online education platform.

Technical Lead for an international online media publishing group

Jamie Oliver, London, United Kingdom – February to September 2017 (jamieoliver.com)

Managing 3 contractors. Lead a migration from a legacy SOAP CRM to a microservices architecture. <u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, TypeScript, PHP (Laravel), RESTful APIs, Redis, Solr, Vue.js, WordPress, Varnish.

Team Leader / Technology Manager for an international NGO

Internews London, United Kingdom – April 2015 to December 2016 (internews.org)

- → Leading the design, development, and delivery of innovation and technology components

 Working with a multidisciplinary team supporting local startups among the most repressive regimes. Leading in delivering news publishing apps. Managing activities' budgets. Speaking at conferences and events.
- → Managing technology team and resources across multiple projects (8 countries)

 Overseeing the recruitment and day-to-day managing a team of 5 technologists. Ensuring planning, setting priorities, and agreeing on detailed work plans, budgets, and schedules. Coaching and mentoring team members. Agile delivery. Responsible for technical architecture and roadmap.

<u>Technology:</u> Node.js, PHP (Laravel), WordPress, Drupal (7/8), Ansible, Nginx, OpenVPN, encryption.

.

Web Application Engineer for an international NGO

Internews Paris, France / London, United Kingdom - Mar. 2009 to Mar. 2015 (internews.org)

Designing, developing & supporting multilingual web applications and custom modules. Integration with social network (Twitter, Facebook) APIs. Writing documentation for users. Deployment and monitoring of secure hosting & video platforms. Facilitating training: website building and digital security (West Africa, MENA).

<u>Technology</u>: Drupal, WordPress, PHP (OOP, MVC), MySQL, Solr, AWS, Vagrant, Nginx, Linux administration

.

Software Engineer for a social networking service designed for a family use **Hellotipi.com** Paris, France – February 2008 to January 2009 (hellotipi.com)

<u>Technology</u>: MySQL, PHP5 (OOP, MVC), XML, Jquery, Ffmpeg, Debian, Linux administration

ICT Projects Manager for a local NGO in Armenia

Fondation KASA Yerevan, Armenia - March 2006 to September 2007 (kasa.am)

Coordinated Computer training in youth training centres. Developed activities in the two major cities. Managed the recruitment of the local team. Provided technical support for training & social programs.

.

Junior Software Engineer for e-training IT projects for an international training centre **Valeo Thermal Systems** Paris, France – March 2005 to February 2006 (<u>valeo.com</u>) Designed & implemented tools for course support creation (virtual classes, e-learning modules).

Education

MSc in Computer Sciences and Innovation

Ecole Supérieure d'Informatique, Electronique, Automatique Paris, France

5 years engineering school in information technologies & electronics (<u>esiea.fr</u>) → *Graduated with first-class honours*.

Foreign languages

French: Mother tongue English: Fluent Spanish: Basic level Arabic: Beginner

Hobbies

Curating <u>a weekly music newsletter</u>. Collecting records (LPs), mostly nerdy noisy music. <u>Photography</u> (film and digital).

Part of the media team of a <u>non-league fan-owned football club</u> in East London.